Finding Aid for the Stafford Leak Warren Papers LSC.0987
UCLA Library Special Collections
- X. Oversize Materials.
  - Additional papers of Dr. Warren, donated by his daughter Mrs. Jane Larson., 1987. (Box 284, Box 285, Box 286, Box 287, Box 288, Box 289, Box 290, Box 291, Box 292, Box 293, Box 294, Box 295, Box 296, Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 300, Box 301)
    - 1) Unusual Letters containing 38 personal letters from family and friends and some printed matter., 1970.; In folder. (Box 295)
    - 2) Important Letters 53 items mostly personal letters from family and colleagues and some printed matter., July 1970-71.; In folder. (Box 295)
    - 3) Important Letters containing 56 items mostly personal correspondence, letters of regret, condolences, recommendation, acceptance of honors and awards, and UCLA administrative affairs., January 1969-1974.; In folder. (Box 295)
    - 4) Manila envelope containing. (Box 295)
      Folder Bikini Memoris with 5 drawings by H.J. Summers and an inscribed photo of naval officer George Lyan.
      Folder State Dept containing 8 documents c. 20pp. about the Trinity test 1945, from Oppenheimer, Leith, etc. declassified 1960.
      Folder Medical History Unit containing 8 items about the Trinity test and SLW's subsequent writings.
      Folder containing 2 black and white photos of the A-bomb blasts above Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
      21 pp about Oak Ridge medical reports 1960.
      10pp. report and correspondence by L.B. Silverman about the Dayton project at Manhattan Engineering District 1962.
      Bibliography to 1943 by Mrs. J. Kyle on the Biological Effects of Radiation.
      3pp. SLW manuscript notes loose.
      8pp. correspondence from Mrs. McFettridge to SLW about his radiology manuscript.
      42 printed documents, forms, reports etc. about radiation exposure, incidents thereof, hazards, treatments, and safeguards, c. 300pp.
    - 1) Brown stab folder containing personal correspondence to SLW and 3 black and white photos of SLW's appointment to the MR committee., 100 pieces. (Box 296)
    - 2) Folded manila envelope, loosely holding 7 black and white contact print sheets and 2 black and white photos along with typescripts of 6 interviews for a KCET TV program on the origin of the Atom bomb plus a clipping and 2 photocopies, in all c. 90pp., June 1970. (Box 296)
    - 3) 2 cans of color projection film spools titled Bikini Excerpts in mailing box., October 5, 1967. (Box 296)
    - Box contains personal effects to wit. (Box 297)
      - 1) WD photo ID., August 26, 1944. (Box 297)
      - 2) Letter of Introduction from the President of the University of Rochester., November 30, 1925. (Box 297)
      - 3)Leather folder stamped in gilt containing photocopy of U.S. Treasury check to SLW for $25,000.00 noting on check Atomic Energy. (Box 297)
      - 4) Small roll of projection film in a box, labelled Rayleigh Jet Dr. Pressman's film 4000 f.p.s. made about by Bell Tel. Lab. From Millie to S.L. Warren., October 1967. (Box 297)
      - 5) 2 sets of military decorations. (Box 297)
      - 6) The SLW medallion in a wooden box. (Box 297)
      - 7) Photo ID badge from the University of Rochester. (Box 297)
      - 8) UCLA distinguished service medallion and wooden base. (Box 297)
      - 9) Plaque commemorating SLW as founding director of the Atomic Energy Project-UCLA. (Box 297)
      - 10) Yellow silk sash with blue rosette and blue fringe, from UCLA. (Box 297)
      - 11) Leather box containing SLW's Legion of Merit medal with two other medal ribbons. (Box 297)
      - 12) Leather box containing SLW's Distinguished Service Medal and ribbon. (Box 297)
    - 1) Small manila envelope Japanese Trip containing tourist ephemera, maps etc., 1962. (Box 298)
    - 2) Shoe box containing 90 items Letters and Clippings of Vi W during war years. (Box 298)
      SLW's green stiff-bound notebook 8 × 5, 72pp. written mostly in ink and a few in pencil, and 23 blank, from Los Alamos to Japan to California-July 12 1945, to October 15 1945.
      24 miscellaneous sheets with manuscript notes, drawings, maps etc. by and to SLW.
      SLW's 2 powers of attorney made over to his wife.
      6 mimeographed texts (2 in Japanese) including Full Translation of Reports on Effect of Atomic Bomb at Hiroshima September 6, 1945 Secret 22pp.
      3pp. carbon of SLW letter to Gavin Hodden describing specific incidents at Hiroshima.
      Typescript 14pp. no title, no author, describing the Hiroshima explosion effects.
      Typescript 15pp. by SLW Preliminary Report Atomic Bomb Investigation November 27, 1945 with 3 cover letters from A1 Riggs and George Darling.
      Map of Nagasaki.
      2 offprints by Yoshio Nishima, 1938 and 1941.
      Offprint by Masao Tsuzuki.
    - 1) Photograph album containing 110 black and white photos of the building of UCLA medical center. (Box 299)
    - 2) 6 large black and white photos of SLW at desk., circa 1955. (Box 299)
    - 3) 2 copies of black and white photo in folder of medical staff at Mass General Hospital both inscribed on the back by SLW. (Box 299)
    - 4) Folder containing. (Box 299)
      Legion of Merit certificate.
      DSM certificate.
      Black and white photo of SLW with Earl Warren inscribed From one Warren to another with best wishes and high regard...1967 by EW.
      TLS to SLW from Ronald Reagan September 1, 1971.
      TLS to SLW from Paul Priolo June 17, 1974.
      Black and white photo inscribed to SLW by Hubert Humphrey.
      Black and white photo inscribed to SLW by Lyndon Johnson.
    - 5) Lithographic reproduction of the Old State Building in DC with clipping. (Box 299)
    - 6) B/w portrait photo of Mrs. SLW in a folder with a press release about SLW winning the Fermi award. (Box 299)
    - 14 (c.) phonograph record of a talk by SLW to the AEC no place., undated (Box 300)
    - 78 black and white glass slides 4 × 3 and one color 35 mm slide and 2 clippings, showing Hiroshima and Nagasaki after the explosions, injuries, physical destruction, maps, charts, equipment etc. (Box 301)
- XI. Personal Library. (Box 308)
  - History of the American Association of Neurological Surgeons. (Box 308)
  - Industrial Medicine on the Plutonium Project., 1951. (Box 308)
  - Atoms for the World. (Box 308)
  - Sourcebook on Atomic Energy., 1950. (Box 308)
  - Atoms in the Family., 1954. (Box 308)
  - Man and Atom. (Box 308)
  - Man and Society in Disaster. (Box 308)
  - Yearbook of the Department of Agriculture. (Box 308)
  - A History of the United States Atomic Energy Commission. (Box 308)
  - Papers in Geophysics. (Box 308)
  - Psychological Warfare. (Box 308)
  - Time, Space and Atoms. (Box 308)
  - Sanity and Survival. (Box 308)
  - Explaining the Atom., 1947. (Box 308)
  - The German Atomic Bomb., 1967. (Box 308)
  - Queen of the Sciences. (Box 308)
  - Oppenheimer: The Story of a Friendship. (Box 308)
  - Fear, War, and the Bomb., 1949. (Box 308)
  - Men and Atoms., 1959. (Box 308)
  - Who Live In Shadow., 1959. (Box 308)
  - The Hydrogen Bomb: The Men, The Menace, The Mechanism., 1954. (Box 308)
  - Selected Materials on Environmental Effects of Producing Electric Power., 1969. (Box 309)
  - Whole Body Counters. (Box 309)
  - Atomic Power and Moral Faith. (Box 309)
  - International Control of Atomic Energy and the Prohibition of Atomic Weapons. (Box 309)
  - Library Planning for Automation. (Box 309)
  - Symposium on Human Problems in The Utilization of Fallout Shelters., 1960. (Box 309)
  - The United States Atomic Energy Commission: What It Is, What It Does. (Box 309)
  - Progress in Nuclear Energy Series VI: Biological Sciences., 1961. (Box 309)
    Volume 3: The Entry of Fission Products into Food Chains
  - The Fundamental Ideas of Chemistry., 1920. (Box 309)
  - Fluid and Electrolyte Therapy. (Box 309)
  - Perils of the Peaceful Atom. (Box 309)
  - A General Account of the Development of Methods of Using Atomic Energy For Military Purposes Under the Auspices of the United States Government. (Box 309)
  - The University of California Los Angeles Campus School of Medicine Atomic Energy Project., 1952. (Box 310)
  - Operation Plumbbob Report., 1966. (Box 310)
  - Proceedings of the Second Interdisciplinary Conference on Selected Effects of a General War., 1969 July. (Box 310)
  - Proceedings of the Third Interdisciplinary Conference on Selected Effects of a General War., 1971 January. (Box 310)
  - Report to The President and the Secretary of Defense on the Department of Defense., 1970 July 1. (Box 310)
  - Medical Research Programs: The Kroc Foundation., 1977. (Box 310)
  - Biological Tolerance to Air Blast and Related Biomedical Criteria., 1965 October 18. (Box 310)
  - Utah Historical Quarterly Vol. 10., 1942. (Box 310)
    Numbers 1-4 January, April, July, October
  - Offsite Ecological Research of the Division of Biology and Medicine - Terrestrial and Freshwater., 1961. (Box 310)
  - UC, Los Angeles Laboratory of Nuclear Medicine and Radiation Biology Annual Report., 1967 July 1-1968 June 30. (Box 310)
  - MedUCLA., 1955. (Box 310)
  - Laboratory of Nuclear Medicine and Radiation Biology, University of California Medical Center, Los Angeles. (Box 310)
  - Foreign Doctors in the Pueblo of Los Angeles., undated (Box 310)
    By Viola Lockhart Warren
  - The Scientific Journal - 300th Anniversary., 1964. (Box 310)
  - Background Material for the Development of Radiation Protection Standards., 1961 September. (Box 310)
  - Learning to Use the Tools: Media Learning Resources at UCLA., 1974 June. (Box 310)
  - UCLA Cancer Center Bulletin., 1976 April-May. (Box 310)
  - John Hopkins Magazine., 1976 September. (Box 310)
  - Health Protection Activities of the Plutonium Project., 1946. (Box 310)
  - UCLA Medicine., 1991. (Box 310)
  - Fifty Years of Medicine at Rochester., 1975. (Box 310)
  - University of California Academic Senate Record of the Assembly. (Box 310)
  - Twenty-second Semiannual Report of the Atomic Energy Commission. (Box 310)
  - Guests. (Box 310)
    Two guest books with names, addresses and remarks. One of the books is from the Third Annual Post-Doctorate Supper and Party (Auspices fo the UCLA Medical School and the Friends International Center) on December 8, 1957 at Dr. and Mrs. Stafford L. Warren's home in Pacific Palisades.
  - The Oak Log Yearbook., 1945. (Box 310)